Jeremy (Ruihan) Wei

HIGHLIGHTS OF QUALIFICATIONS

<u>ruihanwei.github.io/PersonalWebsite</u> • 2263437177 • r25wei@uwaterloo.ca

Engineering, A.I. Specialization • github.com/RuihanWei

- Languages: C#, Python, Java, JavaScript/TypeScript, C/C++, MATLAB

- Technologies: React JS, Redux, Angular JS, Express JS, Node JS, MongoDB, SQL, .NET

Tools: Git, Jira, Jenkins, Heroku, OpenCV, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Azure DevOps Server (TFS), Bitbucket, GitHub, Linux

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern oral/pending offer from Google LLC cancelled due to COVID-19

Incoming C#/C++ Software Developer intern (winter 2021) at Ubisoft

Full Stack Developer | IBM Corp.

Toronto, Canada | Sept. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Developed features and resolved defects for Watson Financial services using JavaScript/TypeScript (React-Redux) frontend, T-SQL and C# backend
- Implemented universal wildcard search and refactored/enhanced all search filters leading to 30% elevated performance
- Implemented user query audit logging, audit log csv exporting following the **REST API** architectural style and drag-and-drop (**React**) logic to retained large clients
- Refactored multi-threaded user state/data migration, email notification logic and user data model modification logic to improve code cleanliness and remove unintended behaviours

Deep Learning Research Developer | Vision and Image Processing Lab, <u>University of Waterloo</u>, Canada | May. 2020 – Aug. 2020

- Developed COVID-19 mobility-based forecasting web application using React JS, Python Flask framework, MongoDB and PyTorch library. Deployed with Heroku (<u>covid-scenario-modelling.herokuapp.com</u>); training scheduled with Unix Cron (<u>github.com/RuihanWei/Canada-COVID-Spread-Modeling-API</u>)
- Developed Convolutional Neural Network and Long Short-Term Memory model for multivariate time series forecasting of COVID-19 spread in Canada in **Python**, utilizing **TensorFlow**, **Keras** and **PyTorch**
- Developed fluid dynamics simulations for viral transmission in C++ under Linux environments, accelerated by graphical neural nets

Software Developer | Focal Healthcare Inc.

Toronto, Canada | Jan. 2019 – April 2019

- Designed, implemented and unit tested a software/hardware dependency/profile modifier in **C#** (UI in **WPF/XAML**), following the **MVVM** architecture
- Projects decreased profile/dependency editing/creation time by 60% and improved development and client support efficiency
- Automated build, release and QA processes with **Python**, **C#**, PowerShell, CMake and MSBuild scripts; Projects improved QA efficiency and reduced installation cycle complexity

Software Developer | Laborie Medical Technologies Inc.

Mississauga, Canada | May 2018 – Aug. 2018

- Developed release notes generation and project baseline analysis for a workflow management tool in **C#** utilizing MVVM and **async processing** (UI in WinForms); refactoring increased data extraction efficiency by **20**%
- Developed RFID scan and hardware noise simulations and performed defect resolution in **C#** for Laborie's core software application (UI in **WPF/XAML**, architecture in MVVM) and hardware emulators

NLP and Robotics Research Developer | Department of Engineering, University of Waterloo Waterloo, Canada | Sept. 2018 – current

- Developing Natural Language Processing variational autoencoder model for verification of financial reports in Python using PyTorch
- Development of a robotic head in **C** with **Raspberry Pi**; established low-level control of motors and encoders through the CAN communication protocol; this will enable future development of a model-predictive controller

PROJECTS (GitHub Links Provided)

ObjectVersionControl Web Application (github.com/RuihanWei/ObjectVersionControl)

2019-2020

- Full stack App that performs real-life "version control" with applications in forensics and personalized object tracking
- Built with the Flask framework, Python and MySQL backend, JavaScript frontend, real-time object detection powered by OpenCV,
 YOLO and TensorFlow; design followed the layered architecture and REST API styles

Gitarmi Freelancing/Project Hosting Web Application

ongoing

 Developing web platform for artists to host and customize digital portfolios and engage in freelancing activites with other users, utilizing Angular JS, Angular Material, Node JS, Express JS and MongoDB

Software Team Lead of NeoWulf: Building an Exoskeletal Grip Assist (github.com/RuihanWei/NeoWulf DoubleSingleFlex) 2018-2019

- Interfaced with Myo armband from Arduino and PC through Bluetooth in **C++** to acquire and process EMG signals and facilitate biometric control of exoskeleton; project allowed a quadriplegic to control finger movements with biceps

EDUCATION

 Candidate for Bachelor of Applied Science, Biomedical Engineering, Artificial Intelligence option (specialization), University of Waterloo